bidclerk.com 2014-02-14

# BidClerk - Privacy Policy

This privacy statement covers the site [bidclerk.com](http://www.bidclerk.com/). Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users' privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices.

  1. What personally identifiable information BidClerk collects.
  2. What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the Web site.
  3. What organization collects the information.
  4. How BidClerk.com uses the information.
  5. With whom BidClerk.com may share user information.
  6. What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information.
  7. What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under BidClerk.com control.
  8. How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact BidClerk Customer Support by Email at [support@bidclerk.com](mailto:support@bidclerk.com "Email BidClerk Support") or by phone at 877.737.6482.

* * *

### Information Collection and Use

#### Information Collection

BidClerk.com is the sole owner of the information collected on BidClerk.com. BidClerk.com collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site.

#### Registration

In order to use this Web site, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to provide contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which he has expressed interest. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender), and unique identifiers (such as, username and password), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site.

#### Order

We request information from the user on our order form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer's orders. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user.

* * *

### Information Use

BidClerk.com uses your information to provide you with the best experience when using the site. Content may be personalized to meet your individual viewing needs. Information is used to ensure that the terms and conditions are abided by. The site may include some adult content such as user feedback and the age of the user during registration is used to block such content. BidClerk.com will also occasionally market various products and services. BidClerk may also distribute your contact information in order to market on your behalf and or to provide directory services to industry participants. You may opt out of marketing and directory services in the My BidClerk BidAlert administration section.

* * *

### Profile

We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the user's personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to our Web site and to direct pertinent BidClerk.com marketing promotions to them. We do not share your profile with other third parties.

* * *

### Cookie Disclosure

#### What's a cookie?

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. A cookie contains a unique number that allows our site to recognize your computer. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once you close your browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on your hard drive for an extended period of time.

#### Accessing the Website

In order to access BidClerk successfully, your browser must be set to "accept all cookies." If you set your browser to "not accept" any cookies, you will not be able to use BidClerk.com. A subscriber is limited to (1) concurrent session cookie and thus may use BidClerk.com on one (1) device at any given time. Access from a second device will invalidate the previous session cookie. Please see the Intellectual Property section in our Terms of Service for policies concerning the sharing of account information. This feature is not for sharing your subscription or access to the Website but is for your convenience. Please see the Intellectual Property Ownership section in our User Agreement for restrictions on the sharing of account information. 

#### Why do we use cookies?

BidClerk uses cookies to check our database to verify your subscription so you can gain access. Cookies allow us to keep track of your user name and password (if you are a subscriber) so you don't have to re-enter that information each time you visit our Website, thereby saving time while on our Website. We also use cookies to save your preferences. Without cookie technology, we would not be able to offer you convenient features such as your saved preferences and searches.

#### Deleting cookies

Deleting cookies means that you may be locked out of your account and lose your preferences. There are a number of software and shareware programs available that are designed to periodically purge cookie files from your hard disk. We do not recommend these applications and, as such, cannot address any resulting support issues that may be related to the use of these programs.

* * *

### Privacy of Email Addresses / Demographic Information

BidClerk will not sell the email list information that is compiled from submissions to this site. Any demographic information provided by or about you in response to a request or inquiry by BidClerk shall not be attributed to you. However, BidClerk may distribute your contact information in order to market on your behalf and or to provide directory services to industry participants. You may opt out of marketing and directory services in the My BidClerk BidAlert administration section.

* * *

### Remarketing in Online Advertising

Third-party vendors, including Google, show BidClerk ads on sites on the Internet. These vendors use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to the BidClerk website. You may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). You may opt out of a third party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

* * *

### Log Files

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information.

* * *

### Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. The main difference between the two is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs are not tied to users' personally identifiable information. In addition, we use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If users would like to opt-out of these emails, please see the Opt-out section.

* * *

### Communications from the Site

#### Special Offers and Updates

We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

#### Newsletter

If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

#### Service Announcements

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.

#### Customer Service

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the user's wishes.

* * *

### Sharing Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site. Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable) We DO NOT share aggregated demographic information.

* * *

### Third Party Advertisers

BidClerk.com does share non-personally identifiable Web site usage information about users.

* * *

### Service Providers

We do partner with other third parties to provide specific services.

* * *

### Business Transitions

In the event BidClerk.com goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via [support@bidclerk.com](mailto:support@bidclerk.com "Email BidClerk Support") or via a prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users' personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection they will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section. 

* * *

### Choice/Opt-out

Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information. For example, our order form has an 'opt-out' mechanism so users who buy a product from us, but don't want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to "Remove" in the subject line in the email or email us at [support@bidclerk.com](mailto:support@bidclerk.com)

-or-

> the user may contact us at 877.737.6482

-or-

-or-

> BidClerk.com  
> 28 N. Clark St.  
> Suite 450  
> Chicago, IL 60602

to opt-out.

The most immediate method is to email us at [support@bidclerk.com](mailto:support@bidclerk.com). Please remember to include the email address or contact number that you would like to have removed.

* * *

### Links

This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, BidClerk.com, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

* * *

### Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used [shared with the contest [survey] sponsors] to notify the winners and award prizes. Anonymous Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Users' personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties.

* * *

### Tell-A-Friend

If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. BidClerk.com will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. BidClerk.com does store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. The friend may contact BidClerk.com at [support@bidclerk.com](mailto:support@bidclerk.com "Email BidClerk Support") to request the removal of this information from our database.

* * *

### Security

This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line. When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just 'surfing'. To learn more about SSL, follow this link [http://www.verisign.com](http://www.verisign.com/). While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added; our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users' information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment in a locked facility. If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to [support@bidclerk.com](mailto:support@bidclerk.com "Email BidClerk Support"). 

* * *

### Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the member information page or by emailing our Customer Support at [support@bidclerk.com](mailto:support@bidclerk.com "Email BidClerk Support"). Or, contact us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

* * *

### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

* * *

### Contact Information

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: 

#### Phone

> 877.737.6482

#### Fax

> 312.577.0902

#### Email

#### Postal Address

> BidClerk.com28 N. Clark St.  
> Suite 450  
> Chicago, IL 60602 Attn: BidClerk Customer Support

#### Support Department
